Guide to the Robert R. Wilson papers, 1936-2000.
Wilson, Robert R. papers, 1936-2000.
- Series II. Correspondence - General/Professional
  - Hewlett, Richard G., AEC, to "Members of the Historical Advisory Committee," re formal letter from the Historical Advisory Committee summarizing the committee's recommendations at the meeting of October 26 [mc], draft of letter [phc]; reply, 10/30/1965 [cc], 11/15/1965 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Heyman, Henry, AEC, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re application for a patent [tls], 2/23/1951 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Heyman, Henry, to R.R.W., C. U., re patent No. 2,899,557 [tls], 8/31/1959 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Hickman, R. W., Harvard University, re reinstallation of cyclotron at Harvard [cc], 11/1/1945 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Hickman, R. W., Harvard University, to R.R.W., re coursework at University of Los Alamos [tls]; reply, 12/4/1945 [cc], 11/27/1945 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Hickman, R. W., Harvard University, to R.R.W., Berkeley, re prospectus of course offerings at Los Alamos [tls]; reply, 1/18/1946 [cc], 12/18/1945 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Hickman, R. W., Harvard University, Ken and Bob, Santa Fe, re cyclotron at Los Alamos [cc, signed], 12/28/1945 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Hickman, R. W., Harvard University, to R.R.W., Oakland, Ca., re receipt of travel expense accounts, greetings [tls], 2/23/1946 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Higinbotham, Dorothy, FAS from Charles D. Coryell re FAS meeting at Harvard [cc], 1/7/1953 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, Dorothy, FAS, to Professor Robert E. Marshak, University of Rochester, re report on NSF meeting [cc, signed], 3/17/1953 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., to R.R.W., Harvard University, re invitation to testify at joint hearings on proposals for a national science program (telegram) [phc], note by J.H.V.V. on recto [als], typed copy of text [cc], 10/16/1945 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W., FAS, from R.R.W., re letter from Mr. Coffin [cc], 1/4/1946 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., FAS, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re election as President, hopes R.R.W. will accept [tls], 9/25/1946 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., to Dr. John A. Simpson, Atomic Scientists of Chicago, Inc., re Federation [cc], 10/2/1946 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., to Dr. Harlow Shapley, Harvard College Observatory, re Federation and new science legislation [cc], 10/21/1946 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., FAS, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re meeting of Administrative Committee [tls], 12/22/1946 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., FAS, from R.R.W., re meeting of Administrative Committee [cc], 10/25/1946 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., FAS, from R.R.W., re Uncle Nick and Bob Bacher [cc], 10/30/1946 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., FAS, to Administrative Committee, re David Hawkins' writeup on policy [tls], 11/4/1946 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., FAS, from R.R.W., re list from Schaffner of points to be covered in discussions [cc]; reply, n.d., "Here is the 'dope.'" [cc], 11/12/1946 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., to R.R.W., Harvard University, re Educational Council (telegram) [phc], 11/20/1946 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., FAS, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re article Meier is working on [tls], 11/27/1946 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., to Joseph Halle Schaffner, Emergency Committee of Atomic Scientists, Inc., re contributions from foundations [cc], 11/27/1946 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., FAS, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re redraft of letter [tls], 1/29/1947 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., FAS, to Michael Straight, The New Republic, re atomic problem [cc], 2/4/1947 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., FAS, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re Baruch's resignation, Lilienthal Report, scientific advisors [tls], 1/15/1947 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., FAS, from R.R.W., re radio broadcast series put on by Dexter Masters [cc], 3/7/1947 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., FAS, from R.R.W., re meeting with administrative committee [cc], 4/24/1947 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., FAS, to R.R.W., C. U. re policy of FAS [tls], 5/13/1947 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., BNL, from R.R.W., re Meier's ideas about the functions of the proposed Executive Secretariat and Secretary [cc], 5/24/1948 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., FAS, to R.R.W., C. U. re invitation to join Scientists' Committee on Loyalty Problems (S.C.L.P.) [tls], prospectus on S.C.L.P. [pi]; reply, 9/29/1948 [cc], 9/13/1948 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., FAS, to "Administrative Committee," re recent Administrative Committee meeting [cc], 9/21/1948 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A.: A. S. Wightman for W. A. H., to R.R.W., re W. A. H. recent letter on S.C.L.P. [mc, signed], prospectus, interim report on S.C.L.P. [mc], list of sponsors, 10/1/1948 [mc], copy of letter sent on SCLP Letterhead September 29, 1948 [mc], 10/2/1948 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., to R.R.W., re concern about U.N. situation and lack of time[tls], memo to Administrative Committee and Council Delegates,11/2/1948, re November meetings [cc], A. H. Shapley, FAS, to R.R.W., C. U., 11/13/1948 re Council meeting 11/28 [tls], preliminary agenda [mc], memo to Adm. Com. From WAHIG, 11/7/[1948] [cc], 10/22/1948 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., BNL, to R.R.W., re FAS proposals for amendments to constitution [mc], 1/16/1949 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., BNL, to Arthur Roberts, re secrecy argument in connection with McMahon Committee [cc], 2/23/1949 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., BNL, to Administrative Committee, re Blackett's book [cc], 3/29/1949 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., BNL, to R.R.W., re attending Harwell Conference at Oxford [tls]; reply, 7/26/1950 [cc], 7/15/1950 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., FAS, to "Marshak and Wilson," re setting up a committee for the FAS relating to Congressional investigations and scientific freedoms as a generalization of academic freedom [cc, signed], 3/8/1953 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., FAS, to "Gentlemen," re meeting 4/23/ [phc], 4/11/1962 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., BNL, from R.R.W., re visits to China [cc]; reply, 3/29/1966 [phc], 3/23/1966 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Higinbotham, W. A., BNL, to R.R.W., re running for president of FAS [als], Tues. (n.d.) (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Hill, David L., FAS, to R.R.W., C. U., re improving procedures of Congressional Investigating Committees [tls]; reply, 10/2/1953 [cc], P. S. on recto [am], 8/13/1953 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Hill, David L., FAS, to R.R.W., C. U., re international control of atomic energy [tls]; D. L. H. to David R. Inglis re international control of atomic energy [cc], 11/10/1953 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Hill, George S., to R.R.W., C. U., re suggestions for FAS [als]; reply, 1/7/1964 [cc], 12/16/1963 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Hill, George S., to R.R.W., C. U., re return of printed Council statement [als], 2/2/1964 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Hill, George S., to R.R.W., C. U., re National Scientific Unit for the reelection of President Johnson [als]; reply, 5/12/1964 [cc], 5/4/1964 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Hill, Payer, Todd School Alumni Association, to "Dear Alumnus," re school closing [mc, signed], [1950] (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Hinkley, J. W[illiam], Research Corporation, to R.R.W., C. U., re course in humanistic physics [tls]; reply, 12/21/1960 [tl], 11/15/1960 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Hinterberger, Hank, Fermilab, to R.R.W., NYC, re recollections of the highlights of his engineering activities during the construction phase of Fermilab [tls], 8/6/1981 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Hirao, Yasuo, National Institute of Radiological Sciences, to R.R.W., C. U., re use of Bragg-peak of proton and heavy ions for medical applications [fax]; reply, 8/23/1994 [pl], 7/25/1994 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Hoddeson, Lillian, Fermilab, to R.R.W., re article on history of the doubler [tls]; reply, 12/11/1986 [phc], 4/11/1986 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Hoddeson, Lillian, Fermilab, to R.R.W., C. U., re reviewing manuscript Critical Assembly: A Technical History of Los Alamos during the Oppenheimer Years [tls], 11/18/1988 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Hoddeson, Lillian, Fermilab, to R.R.W., re Third International Symposium on the History of Particle Physics [tls], 5/28/1991 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Hoddeson, Lillian, "A Technical History of Los Alamos during the War Years, 1943-1944": Mr. Andrew Martin, Cambridge University Press, from R.R.W., review of book [pm], 11/12/1991 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Hodes, Elizabeth, Santa Barbara, to R.R.W., Fermilab, re comparison and evaluation of contributions of the American Association of Scientific Workers and Federation of American Scientists [tls], 11/20/1981 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Hoffmann, Frederic de, Santa Fe, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re declassification of report No. LA-76 (assigned LADC #267) [mc], 1/15/1947 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Hoffmann, Frederic de, Santa Fe, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re declassification of report No. LA-27 (assigned LADC #253) [mc], 1/15/1947 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Hoffmann, Frederic de, Santa Fe, to C. Redman, University of Chicago and D. Saxon, Clinton Engineer Works, re declassification of Report LADC 263 [cc], 1/27/1947 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Hoffmann, Frederic de, Santa Fe, to R.R.W., Harvard University, re declassification of LADC Reports 253, 273, 267 P.S. [al], 1/27/1947 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Hoffmann, Frederic de, Princeton University, to R.R.W., C. U., re NRC Report on Particle and Quantum Detectors [tls]; reply, 7/18/1950 [cc], 7/18/1950 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Hofstadter, Robert, Stanford University, to R.R.W., C. U., re calculations and results on showers and transition curves in the range of energies 100-500 Mev [tls]; reply, 6/13/1951 [cc], 5/12/1951 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Hofstadter, Robert, CERN, from R.R.W., re getting him a copy of Freeman Dyson's "Advanced Quantum Mechanics" [als]; reply, 2/25/1951, plus reprints [cc], 2/19/1959 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Hofstadter, Robert, CERN, to R.R.W., re success in scattering electrons from protons at high energies [als], 6/19/1959 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Hofstadter, Robert, CERN, from R.R.W., re resume of work [cc], 9/27/1960 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Hofstadter, Robert, Stanford University, to R.R.W., C. U., re "Scattering of High Energy Electrons by Protons," lab news [tls], 10/12/1960 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Hofstadter, Robert, Stanford University to Dr. H. F. Schopper, C. U., re delay in sending results, lab news [cc], 2/27/1961 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Hofstadter, Robert, Stanford University to Drs. D. H. Olson, H. F. Schopper and R.R.W., C. U., re "Electromagnetic Properties of the Proton and Neutron" and some discrepancies [cc], 3/13/1961 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Hofstadter, Robert, Stanford University to Professor Hans Bethe, C. U., re values of total neutron cross sections [thermo-fax]; reply, R. H. from R.R.W., 4/3/1961 [cc], 3/13/1961 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Hofstadter, Robert, Stanford University, to Drs. George Bishop, Geoffrey Chew, L. I .Schiff, Sergio Fubini, Wayne Gruner, Norman Ramsey, Victor Weisskopf, and R.R.W., re 50th anniversary conference celebrating the birth of the atomic concept and possibility of changing date for International Conference on Nucleon Structure [phc]; reply, 9/24/1962 [cc], 9/18/1962 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Hofstadter, Robert, Stanford University, to Drs. George Bishop, Geoffrey Chew, Sergio Fubini, Wayne Gruner, Norman Ramsey, L. I .Schiff, Victor Weisskopf, and R.R.W., re Nucleon Structure Conference [phc], proposed program [tm], bulletins 1A & 1B [phc]; reply, 2/12/1963 [thermo-fax], 1/9/1963 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Hofstadter, Robert, Stanford University, from R.R.W., re LNS staff participation at conference [cc], 3/27/1963 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Hofstadter, Robert, Stanford University, to R.R.W., C. U., re chairing Special Session on Experimental Methods in High Energy Scattering at International Conference on Nucleon Structure [tls], information on conference program [phc]; reply, 4/30/1963 [cc], 4/23/1963 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Holcomb, Donald F., C. U., from B. D. McDaniel, re report of space need for LNS through 1969 [cc, signed], 12/9/1964 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Holton, Gerald, International Academy of the History of Science, to R.R.W., C. U., re possible donation [tls]; thank you, 3/2/1982 [tls], 12/18/1981 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Holton, Gerald, History of Science Society, to R.R.W., C. U., re accepting membership in the Society's new Council of Friends of the History of Science [tls], note of acceptance, 9/25/1982 [am], 9/13/1982 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Holton, Gerald, History of Science Society, to R.R.W., C. U., re financial appeal to support Society [tls], 6/6/1984 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Holton, Gerald, Harvard University, to R.R.W., C. U., re 80th birthday [tls], 2/24/1994 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Holton, Gerald, to R.R.W.: draft of form letter [fax], note by Spencer on recto [als]; same letter on Friends of the Center For the History of Physics letterhead [fax], note by Spencer on recto [als], 5/19/1994 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Horn, David, Israeli Physical Society (IPS), to R.R.W., re acknowledgement of letter on behalf of Mr. Sami Kilani [phc], 1/12/1986 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Hornig, Donald F., Office of Science and Technology, to R.R.W., C. U., re report from Panel on Meson Factories [tls], 3/19/1964 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Hornig, Donald F., Cambridge, Mass., to R.R.W., C. U., re 50th anniversary of the first bomb celebration at Los Alamos [tls], 2/23/1995 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Hospital, Ralph, from R.R.W., re volunteering staff of LNS for civil defense program [cc]; reply, 1/26/1951 [tls]; R.R.W. to R. H., re serving in branch of staff devoted to radiological studies [cc], 1/16/1951 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Hough, Paul, to R.R.W., re closed-book exam and new life style, lab news, note on spark counters [als]; reply, 11/17/1949 [cc], 10/11/1949 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Hough, Paul, to R.R.W., re deuterated wax, congratulations on the mesons, thesis, current research [als], 12/7/1949 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Hough, Paul, to R.R.W., re congratulations on arrival of Jonathan, thesis drawings, current experiments [als], 1/17/[1950] (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Hough, Paul, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, to R.R.W., C. U., request for recommendation for NSF fellowship [als]; thank you, 4/26/[1960] [als], 10/12/ [1959] (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Householder, A. S., Oak Ridge National Laboratory, to R.R.W., C. U., re Monte Carlo Conference [tls]; A. S. H. to R.R.W., 5/20/1949, re change of dates for conference [tls], tentative program [pi]; reply, 5/31/1949 [cc], 5/19/1949 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Howard, Frederick T., Oak Ridge National Laboratory, to R.R.W., C. U., re information for directory of cyclotrons [tls], 5/19/1958 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Huang, K., Princeton, drawing and note [als], 10/29/1965 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Hulse, M. L., C. U., from [Hans A. Bethe], re draft on campus planning and development [tl], 7/9/1951 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Humphreys, John W., C. U., from R.R.W., re addition to LNS [cc], 9/10/1964 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Hunt, Chas. B., The Johns Hopkins University, to Dr. John D. Roberts, CIT, re comments on annual report of committee [phc], 12/2/1965 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Huntoon, R. D., National Bureau of Standards, from R.R.W., re abstract for APS meeting [cc], abstract [cc], 4/17/1961 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Hurwitz, H[enry], Jr., General Electric, to R.R.W., C. U., re draft of report of ORNL Advisory Committee for Applied Nuclear Physics [tls], report [cc]; reply, 11/28/1956 [cc], 11/21/1956 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Hutchisson, Journal of Applied Physics, to R.R.W., Princeton University, re paper "Theory of the Cyclotron" [tls]; reply, draft, 9/26/1940 [als], 9/19/1940 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Hutchisson, Journal of Applied Physics, to R.R.W., Princeton University, re paper "Theory of the Cyclotron" [tls]; notice of publication charge [phc], 10/7/1940 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Hutchisson, Journal of Applied Physics, to R.R.W., Princeton University, re paper "Theory of the Cyclotron" [tls]; reply, draft, 10/?/1940, [als], biography, draft [am], 10/7/1940 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Ice, Carol R., Burlingham, N.Y., to R.R.W., Ithaca, re article on Fermilab [als], 10/12/1987 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Ilakovac, K., Institut Ruder Boskovic, to R.R.W., C. U., re possibility of some of his staff working at Cornell [tls]; reply, 6/30/1955 [cc], 5/24/1955 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Inglis, David R., BNL, to R.R.W., C. U., re representation of FAS at upcoming meetings with European colleagues [tls], D. R. I. to V. F. Weisskopf, Eidgenosische Technische Hochschule, Zurich, re two communications from Crowther inviting FAS to send observer to the first general assembly of the World Federation of Scientific Workers at Prague, Sept. 21-24, information about program [cc], 7/28/1948 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Inglis, David R., BNL, to R.R.W., C. U., re need for R.R.W. to represent FAS in Europe [tls], 8/20/1948 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Inglis, David R., BNL, to R.R.W., C. U., re correction of dates for Paris meeting [tls], note [al], 8/30/1948 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Inglis, David R., Johns Hopkins University, to R.R.W., LNS, re reminder FAS needs reply [tls], 9/7/1948 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Inglis, David R., Johns Hopkins University, to R.R.W., LNS, re UN facilitation of contacts of representatives of non-governmental organizations [tls], 9/9/1948 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Ione, Amy, John F. Kennedy University, to R.R.W., Ithaca, re slides of his artwork [tls], 8/3/1995 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Ivenenko, I. L. to R.R.W., C. U., re conference in Moscow (in Russian) [tls], [1957] (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Ives, Irving M., United States Senate, to R.R.W., C. U., re confirmation of David Lilienthal as Chairman of AEC [tls], 2/14/1947 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Jackson, J. D[ave], Superconducting Super Collider (SSC), to R.R.W., Ithaca, re possible visit [tls], 7/29/1985 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Jackson, J. D[ave], Annual Review of Nuclear and Particle Science, to R.R.W., Ithaca, re invitation to contribute a "Prefatory Chapter to Volume 44" [pls]; reply, 1/25/1993 [pl], 11/2/1992 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - [Jacob], Maurice, to R.R.W., re visit to Tesuque, family news, [als], 8/29/[n.y.] (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jacob, M[aurice], CERN, to Professor Buckel, European Physical Society (EPS), re serving on Executive Board of EPS, planning workshop with APS in Middle East [phc], note to R.R.W. on recto [al], 4/9/1987 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jacob, M[aurice], from R.R.W., C. U., re interest in workshop proposed for Athens [phc], 4/15/1987 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jacob, M[aurice], CERN, to Professor Buckel, European Physical Society (EPS), re proposed workshop [phc], 5/26/1987 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jacob, M[aurice], CERN, to Dr. H. Lustig (APS), re interest in proposed workshop [phc], 6/3/1987 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - [Jacob], Maurice, to R.R.W., re visit to Davis, Calif., work in lab, proposed workshop [als], 6/20/[1987] (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jacob, M[aurice], CERN, from R.R.W., C. U., re "Mediterranean Workshop" plans after APS Executive Committee meeting [phc], Harry Lustig, APS, to R.R.W., Ithaca, 6/18/1987, re Mediterranean Workshop [tls], proposal for workshop [phc], minutes of APS meeting, 6/4/1987 (draft) [phc]; reply, 7/10/1987 [tls], P.S. [tl]; R.R.W. to M. J., 8/1/1987 (draft) [als, phc], M. J., CERN, to R.R.W., 7/10/1987 [phc], note on recto M. J. [phc], R.R.W. to H. L. on recto [phc]; M. J., CERN, to R.R.W., 5/18, 21/1987 [phc], M. J. to W. Buckel, 5/26/87 [phc], M. J., CERN, to H. Lustig, APS, 6/3/1987 [phc], 6/25/1987 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jacob, M[aurice], CERN, from R.R.W., re progress on Mediterranean workshop (2 copies) [phc], Harry Lustig, APS, to Werner Buckel, EPS, 9/22/1987 [phc]; reply, 9/25/1987 [als], 9/22/1987 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jacob, M[aurice], CERN, to R.R.W., C. U., re Mediterranean workshop [telemail printout], R.R.W. to Harry Lustig (note on recto) [als], 9/25/1987 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jacob, M[aurice], CERN, to R. Bok, EPS, and R. Salmeron, EPS, re reactions to proposed workshop [tls], 10/20/1987 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jacob, M[aurice], CERN, to R.R.W., C. U., re progress on Workshop venture [tls], 10/30/1987 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jacob, Maurice, CERN, to R.R.W., re visit to U. S. and Fermilab, Thanksgiving greetings, comment on good work with APS [als], originals of M. J. letters to: Professor Buckel, 4/9/1987 [phc], notes on recto [al], R.R.W., 5/9, 18, 21/1987 [als], 12/2/[1987] (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - [Jacob], Maurice, to R.R.W., C. U., re trp to Luxor [post card], 12/2/[1987] (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - [Jacob], Maurice, CERN, to R.R.W., re card from Egypt, attempt to trigger cooperative effort between APS and EPS, note for Europhyics News, Dirae event in London, family news [als]; reply, draft, n.d., [als]; second reply, draft, n.d. [als], 12/4/[1987] (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jacob, Maurice, to R.R.W., re progress with EPS [als], M. J., CERN from Endre Lillithun, EPS, 11/24/1987 [phc], 12/9/[1987] (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jacob, M[aurice], CERN, to R.R.W., C. U., re progress on Workshop [tls], 12/16/1987 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jacob, M[aurice], CERN, to R.R.W., C. U., re new position at EPS, progress on Workshop [tls]; reply, 4/12/1988 [phc], 3/31/1988 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jacob, M[aurice], EPS, to R.R.W., C. U., re manuscript of talk at Lausanne [tls], instructions [phc], 9/21/1994 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - [Jacob], Maurice, to R.R.W., re picture taken during Schopper's test, Franco-German settlement, Italians, European merger, family news [als], 10/26/1994 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jacob, Maurice, CERN, to R.R.W., C. U., re proceedings of the EPS Conference on "Large Facilities in Physics" [tls], 12/14/1994 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - [Jacob], Maurice, CERN, to R.R.W., re American Philosophical Society address on Hiroshima, family news, Sinai meeting [als], 2/13/[n.y.] (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - [Jacob], Maurice, CERN, to R.R.W., re wishes for good health, physics reports, Oppenheimer program [als], 11/28/[n.y.] (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - [Jacob], Maurice, to R.R.W., Christmas card [als], n.d. (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jacobs, Whitney, C. U., to Mr. John Lear, Saturday Review, re material relating to the problem of teaching science to non-science majors [phc], 4/6/1965 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Jacobsen, Carlyle F., National Research Council, to Committee on Disaster Studies, re information for new members of committee [mc], 7/25/1952 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Jacobsen, Carlyle F., National Research Council, to R.R.W., C. U., re upcoming meetings [tls], 9/19/1952 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Jacobsen, Carlyle F., National Research Council, to "Members of the Committee on Disaster Studies," re agenda for meeting 10/9/1952 [cc]; reply, 10/8/1952 [cc], 10/1/1952 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Jacobsen, J. C., Universitetets Institut for Teoretisk Fysik, Copenhagen, to R.R.W., C. U., re plans for an electron accelerator [tls]; reply, 10/1/1953 [cc], 8/25/1953 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - James, Ralph A., UCB, from R.R.W., re notice of position available in nuclear chemistry [cc], 2/25/1948 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Jamison, William A., University of Rochester, re upcoming conference [mc], 3/17/1960 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Jehle, H[erb], Theor. Physics University, Munich, to R.R.W., re May 30 Science article, news of colleagues in the East, German problems [als], n.d. (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Jenkins, Andy, Shidoni Sculpture, to R.R.W., NYC, re interest in Shidoni Gallery [tls], 12/14/[n.y.] (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Jenkins, F. A., UCB, Department of Physics, re speaker for January 19th [tls], 1/7/1938 (Box 2, Folder 73)